<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- generator="FeedCreator 1.7.2 enhanced" -->
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>CELOS RSS feed</title>
        <description>This is the default RSS feeds of CELOS Website</description>
        <link>http://www.celos.ac.in/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 13:08:24 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>FeedCreator 1.7.2 enhanced</generator>
        <managingEditor>editor@celos.ac.in (Feed Editor)</managingEditor>
        <item>
            <title>Optics fair 2011</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Optics-fair-20113</link>
            <description> Optics fair 2011 is all set to take place at the International School of Photonics on December 8 and 9.There are a lot of surprises awaiting this year&#039;s participants.Around 1000 students from 25 different schools are expected to participate. Registration opens : 23 November 2011 Registration can also be done on the spot. Schools are requested to confirm their participation at the earliest for availing convenient slots.Confirmation can be done over phone or by e-mail. Optics Quiz at 2:00 PM on December 8,2011.</description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (Kavitha K G)</author>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 11:36:32 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Optics-fair-20113</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Optics fair</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?2011-11-21</link>
            <description> Optics fair is an annual educational outreach program organised jointly by the ISP-CELOS-SPIE and ISP-OSA Student Chapter.The two day event is aimed at providing the students an opportunity to observe and understand experiments that have lead to the formulation of theories in the field of optics.The fair has been structured to address the requirements of students of all age group.There are sections for each category of students : Kids Section (Class III - VII), High School (Class VIII-X), Higher Secondary Section (Class XI-XII).In addition there is a General Section meant for students of all age group.Every year hundreds of school students from in and around Cochin become a part of the event. Glimpses from Optics Fair 2010</description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (Kavitha K G)</author>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 09:53:01 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?2011-11-21</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Centre-of-Excellence-in-Lasers-and-Optoelectronic-Sciences</link>
            <description>Cochin University of Science and Technology (CUSAT) is one of the few institutions in India that have facilities for R&amp;D activities and manpower training in Photonics and related fields. In recognition of the outstanding work carried out by a group of teachers and researchers in photonics and related subjects, the University Grants Commission (UGC) identified CUSAT as a &quot;University with Potential for Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences&quot; in March 2002. Following this selection by University Grants Commission, CUSAT established a separate and independent &quot;Centre of Excellence in Lasers &amp; Optoelectronic Sciences&quot; (CELOS) in the month of July 2002. The activities under the CELOS have been jointly proposed by the International School of Photonics (ISP), Department of Physics and Department of Electronics in CUSAT. Based on the recommendations of the experts, UGC has made a budgetary allocation of Rs. 35.456 million towards the R &amp; D activities at the above Centre. As approved by the Expert Committee of the UGC, CELOS has established a National Facility centered around “Tsunami” a Spectra Physics make Ti:Sapphire pico/subpicosecond laser system with an amplifier. &quot;Tsunami&quot; is pumped by 5W “Millenium” diode pumped solid state laser. The output from the &quot;Tsunami&quot; seed laser is further amplified by &quot;Spitfire&quot; a chirped pulse amplifer which is pumped by &quot;Empower&quot; a 30W Q-switched DPSS Nd:YLF laser. The final amplified ultrashort pulses have 70 femtosecond pulse duration and an energy of ~ 2.5mJ per pulse at 1KHz repitition rate. Research activities have been initiated by CELOS in the fields of Optical Fiber Amplifier, Fiber Optic Sensors, Photonic Materials, Microwave Photonics, Laser produced Plasma, Nonlinear Processes, Biophotonics and related fields. At present CELOS has two Research Associates, two Senior Research Fellows and four Junior Research Fellows. Another major activity of CELOS is the conduct of the five year integrated M.Sc degree course in Photonics. UGC has set apart an amount of Rs. 19.4 million specifically for this purpose out of the total grant of Rs. 50 million. Six batches of 20 students each have so far joined the course. The first batch completed the course and passed out from the Centre in July 2007. The participating schools/departments in CELOS are: International School of Photonics, CUSAT Department of Electronics, CUSAT Department of Physics, CUSAT    </description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2006 13:47:37 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Centre-of-Excellence-in-Lasers-and-Optoelectronic-Sciences</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Student Nishant</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Nishant</link>
            <description>  Batch - 4 Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin - 682022. Mobile: 9447701904 Email: imnishant.celos@gail.com    Nishant is a student of IXth semester of 5 years Integrated MSc course in Photonics in CELOS. He joined CELOS in the 4th batch of the Integrated M.Sc. course in 2005 and is expected to complete the course in 2010.</description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:43:01 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Nishant</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Student Neelima</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Neelima</link>
            <description>Batch - 4 Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin - 682022. Mobile: Email:         Neelima is a student of IXth semester of 5 years Integrated MSc course in Photonics in CELOS. She joined CELOS in the 4th batch of the Integrated M.Sc. course in 2005 and is expected to complete the course in 2010.  </description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:42:42 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Neelima</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Student Mahesh</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Mahesh</link>
            <description>Batch - 4 Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin - 682022. Mobile: Email:         Mahesh is a student of IX semester of 5 years Integrated MSc course in Photonics in CELOS. He joined CELOS in the 4th batch of the Integrated M.Sc. course in 2005 and is expected to complete the course in 2010.  </description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:42:28 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Mahesh</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Student Priyamvada</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Priyamvada</link>
            <description>Batch - 4 Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin - 682022. Mobile: Email: priyamvada.cusat@gmail.com , v.priyam@celos.ac.in     I joined CELOS in 2005. At present I am in my tenth semester of the 5 Year Integrated MSc degree course in Photonics and would be completing my course in May 2010. Currently, I am doing my Master thesis project in IISC,Bangalore.  My work is investigating whether a CD-R sample can be used for Bio sensing and Strain sensing measurements.    My areas of interest are Bio Photonics, Plasmonics, Photonic Crystals and Non Linear Optics. I have done a mini project titled  Photoelasticity for strain measurements during the sixth semester of the course under the guidance of Dr. V.P.N.Nampoori, ISP, CUSAT. I have done another project in TIFR, Mumbai in Mass Spectroscopy. After I graduate, I plan to join a reputed institute for doing my doctoral research.     During the course, I have taken seminars on: Organic LED Black Body Radiation. Photodynamic Therapy   Bio Imaging Photoelasticity experiments for measuring stress in different objects. Photonic Crystals. Fibre Bragg gratings Laser applications in medicine etc. I am a student member of the International Society for Optical Engineering (SPIE), the Optical Society of America (OSA) and IEEE.</description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:41:08 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Priyamvada</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Student Rajitha</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Rajitha</link>
            <description>Batch - 4 Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin - 682022. Mobile: Email:         Rajitha is a student of IXth semester of 5 years Integrated MSc course in Photonics in CELOS. She joined CELOS in the 4th batch of the Integrated M.Sc. course in 2005 and is expected to complete the course in 2010.  </description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:40:03 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Rajitha</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Student Rose</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Rose</link>
            <description>Batch - 4 Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin - 682022. Mobile:  Email: rosemary.abraham@gmail.com; mary.rose@celos.ac.in      Rose is a student of IXth semester of 5 years Integrated MSc course in Photonics in CELOS. She joined CELOS in the 4th batch of the Integrated M.Sc. course in 2005 and is expected to complete the course in 2010.</description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:39:35 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Rose</guid>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Student Shahid</title>
            <link>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Shahid</link>
            <description>Batch - 4 Centre of Excellence in Lasers and Optoelectronic Sciences, Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin - 682022. Mobile: Email:         Shahid is a student of IX semester of 5 years Integrated MSc course in Photonics in CELOS. He joined CELOS in the 4th batch of the Integrated M.Sc. course in 2005 and is expected to complete the course in 2010.  </description>
            <author>feed@celos.ac.in (celos webmaster)</author>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <guid>http://celos.ac.in/index.php?Student-Shahid</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
